MARC ANDRÉ LEROY

Robotics Engineer – Microengineering EPFL Graduate

Lausanne area, Switzerland Personal address, email and phone number upon request, please reach out via LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/marclerov93, malerov.github.io



SUMMARY

Having had a **multidisciplinary** engineering education, my curiosity is attracted by the fields of **robotics**, **control systems** and **aerospace**. I am an open-minded person with **international** experience and my **language skills** suggest assignments in a multinational environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pix4D S.A.Senior IoT Engineer (initially Hardware Engineer)

Lausanne, Switzerland
01/2018 – Present

- Developed a solution of distributed, yet synchronized **IoT cameras** for daily construction site mapping, aiding BIM / Construction Site Managers in critical decision-making
- Worked in a small team of 5, handling diverse tasks as the product evolved and the business grew (and eventually the team)
- Integrated and fused sensors (e.g. IMU, GNSS, camera) for state estimation using C/C++/Python
- Conducted mechanical design using Autodesk Inventor and PCB development/verification with KiCAD
- Managed product manufacturing, workshop and stock levels, business development, and pre-sales / customer support leveraging language skills
- With the team growing, focused on R&D, improving state estimation algorithms to provide accurate, noise-rejecting data with low-cost sensors to keep the manufacturing cost of the product within its budget
- Mentored a graduate student intern in developing an edge Al algorithm (TensorFlow Lite) for image quality assessment and data throughput optimization
- Led international certification efforts, achieving approvals for different markets, namely CE/RED (EN 301 489, EN 301 908-1, EN 303 413, EN 62311, EN 62368-1, EN 60950-22, EN 60529), FCC/ISED (radio and EMC §15B + ICES-003) and KC
- Sole embedded software / firmware engineer (RTOS, BLE, I²C, USB, FUOTA, etc.) of multiple cell phone accessories, enabling reliable inputs for a photogrammetry pipeline

NASA Ames Research Center

Mountain View, United States of America 02/2017 – 08/2017

- Developed **novel locomotion control algorithms** in the Dynamic Tensegrity Robotics Lab within the Intelligent Robotics Group
- Supported the manufacturing and testing of a tensegrity robot that will be used in future NASA missions
- Presented work at the Structurally Adaptive Tensegrity Robots workshop (07/2017) during the NASA/ESA Conference on Adaptive Hardware and Systems held at the Pasadena California Institute of Technology

Universo S.A. - Swatch Group

La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland 07/2014 – 07/2014

Warehouseman

Research Scholar

- Completed an internship utilizing Numerical Control (NC) machines, lathes, mills, and drills
- Manufactured and repaired components using various machining tools

Swiss Armed Forces Command Support Organization Jassbach and Zimmerwald, Switzerland *Private First Class Strategic Radio Explorer* 10/2011 – 08/2012

- Fulfilled full military obligations as a Swiss citizen in the Center of Electronic Operations
- Worked with classified equipment
- Instructed new and returning privates on the use of the equipment

EDUCATION

Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Lausanne, Switzerland 09/2015 – 09/2017

MSc in Microengineering

Major in Robotics and Autonomous Systems, minor in Space Technologies

Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

BSc in Microengineering

Lausanne, Switzerland 09/2012 – 07/2015

Focus on Systems and Control, Manufacturing Engineering, Electronics and Photonics

SKILLS

- Robotics: Systems Engineering, Mechanical Design, Kinematics, Dynamics, Actuators, Sensors, Linux, Communication Protocols (e.g. Bluetooth Low Energy, TCP, UDP, USB, I²C, SPI, UART, GPIO), Microcontrollers (e.g. ESP32, AVR, Nordic, Zephyr, FreeRTOS, RP2040, Arduino, over-the-air firmware updates), Single-board Computers (e.g. BeagleBone, Raspberry Pi, NVIDIA Jetson Nano), Electronics, Signal/Image Processing, Computer Vision, Sensor Fusion, Control, State Estimation, Localization, Navigation, Locomotion, Manipulation, Haptic Interfaces, Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning
- Control Systems: Linear, Nonlinear, Optimal, Adaptive, Model Predictive, Central Pattern Generators
- Computer-Aided Design and Manufacturing: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, CATIA, Fusion 360, KiCAD, 3D printing, Soldering
- Programming and Scripting: C, C++, Python, Bash, OpenCV, TensorFlow Lite, Matlab, Simulink, Simscape, LabVIEW, Modelica, Assembly
- Productivity: Git, Unit Testing, Docker, LaTeX, Microsoft Office Tools (Excel, PowerPoint, Word)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Master's thesis: Manufacturing, Control and Testing of a Tensegrity Robot for Planetary Landing and Exploration – My Master's thesis was a collaboration between NASA Ames Research Center and EPFL's Biorobotics Laboratory. The innovative results of my work were also presented in a conference and in public outreach activities throughout my time at NASA Ames Research Center
- Semester projects:
 - o CleanSpace One capture system dynamics and design I performed reliability simulations to optimize the shape of a satellite's subsystem. My work was included in a <u>publication</u> I co-authored presented at the 2017 International Astronautical Congress in Adelaide, Australia
 - o *Model of energetic cost against rough terrain and perturbations* I conducted a study on how the energy consumption of a biologically inspired exoskeleton could be reduced
 - o Design of an adaptive structure for multirotors to transport packages of different sizes I designed and manufactured a modular drone structure that can fit different packages

LANGUAGES

French: Native language
Portuguese: Native language
English: Native language
German: Advanced (C1)
Spanish: Intermediate (B1)

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Selected participant in two space engineering international workshops:
 - o Swiss Space Center (09/2016): built a ground station to receive satellite signals
 - o Bauman Moscow State Technical University (07/2016): *Robotics Group Leader* for a team of 8 students
- Part-time Teaching Assistant at EPFL (09/2014 12/2016) in multiple courses taught in French or English for 1st and 2nd year Bachelor students
- Member of various **student associations** throughout my education:
 - o MSc in Microengineering Students' representative (09/2016 09/2017)
 - o Treasurer for "Dynamic" (05/2015 06/2016)
 - o Staff Manager at the "LudIC" events (05/2013 06/2016)
- Hobbies: Tennis, Cuban Salsa dance, Windsurfing, music player (drums)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

31 years old – Married – Father – Swiss and Brazilian dual citizenship – All military obligations already fulfilled